KEVIN MACKEY

DATA ANALYST

) 4

443-617-8915



Mackeyk8@winthrop.edu



LinkedIn



GitHub

ABOUT ME

Healthcare data analyst with over 3 years of experience acquiring, and transforming data into insightful analytics, workflow processes and creating proactive solutions to improve workflow. My primary professional focus is to utilize my leadership and technical strengths to improve business processes. I enjoy problem-solving, gathering, organizing, and analyzing information, working in groups, and contributing to project strategies. I am self-motivated, open-minded and eager to learn.

DATA EXPERIENCE

July 2022 - Present

Data Analyst Apprentice • Nashville Software School

Six-month Intensive part-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and web scraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2021 - Present

Quality Analyst • Veterans Evaluation Services

- Influenced process improvements of large-scale reprocessing of medical claims
- Analyze, organize and interpret provider data via SQL to improve efficiency metrics
- Collaborate with medical providers and outside teams to ensure a seamless workflow

August 2020 - October 2021

Quality Assurance Specialist • QTC Management Inc.

- Provide quality assurance review for medical disability claims for the VA
- Mentored new employees and created presentations for company updates
- Maintained Veteran/Provider information via Excel

KEY SKILLS

- SQL
- PYTHON
- EXCEL
- TABLEAU
- POWER BI
- GIT/GITHUB
- AGILE METHODOLOGY
- HELATHCARE REVENUE
 CYCLE MANAGEMENT

PROJECTS

GDP & Internet Usage Data (Python)

Lahman Baseball Dataset (SQL)

Housing Market 2018 (Tableau)

Squirrel Dataset (PowerBI)

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School
Data Analytics

Winthrop University

Bachelor Of Science (General Biology)